aapt.com.au 2016-12-17

# Privacy Policy | AAPT

This Privacy Policy is current and effective from 12 March 2014.

AAPT and its related bodies corporate (AAPT) are committed to the privacy of its customer's records and for your information we have documented AAPT's information handling practices below. Please contact AAPT on (02) 9009 9009 if you wish to discuss any aspect of AAPT's information handling practices.

## The Australian Privacy Principles

AAPT is bound by the Privacy Act 1988 and the Australian Privacy Principles in that Act.  This Privacy Policy sets out how we manage your personal information in an open and transparent way, in accordance with the Australian Privacy Principles.

  * The kinds of personal information held by AAPT
  * How AAPT collects personal information
  * Unsolicited personal information
  * What are the consequences of not providing Personal Information?
  * Collection Notices
  * Use of your personal information
  * Direct marketing
  * Contracting out services and disclosures
  * Your personal information in overseas locations
  * How you can access your personal information
  * You may remain anonymous
  * Security of your personal information
  * Security of your information while online
  * Cookies
  * Security of stored information
  * Other websites
  * Website access logs
  * Changes to this Privacy Policy
  * Privacy Complaints
  * Organisational Details

## The kinds of personal information held by AAPT

AAPT only collects personal information from you that we reasonably require to perform or is directly related to our functions. The personal information AAPT holds about you will depend on the services you request from AAPT and the use that you make of those services.

The information AAPT may collect includes:

  * contact details (such as your name, address, position, employer, email address, fax number and contact phone numbers);
  * your date of birth;
  * your social media user name (if you interact with AAPT via social media platforms);
  * account name and account and routing number held by financial institutions from which payments for services provided by AAPT are made and information obtained as a result of credit checks which you authorise us to carry out;
  * records of communications between you and AAPT relating to services provided by AAPT to you;
  * phone call recordings (only if you have given permission);
  * records of your use of the services provided by AAPT to you;
  * billing statements.

## How AAPT collects personal information

AAPT generally collects personal information as a result of individuals contacting and/or liaising with AAPT in their capacity as employees, principals, agents, directors or business owners for the purposes of enquiring about or acquiring services from AAPT. AAPT may also collect personal information in connection with AAPT events, promotions or marketing activity (such as competitions). 

AAPT no longer purchases personal information from list rental companies, but we may still use list data that we have previously purchased (except where you have opted out).

AAPT may also collect personal information from third parties such as:

  * resellers of telecommunication services;
  * credit providers or credit reporting agencies contacted by us (or by external service providers on our behalf) in the course of carrying out a credit check;
  * other entities who provide services to us which are related to the provision of telecommunication services provided to you;
  * government agencies which administer laws regulating telecommunication service providers, or complaint resolution processes established under those laws;
  * independent sales organisations; and
  * list rental companies.

## Unsolicited personal information

Most of the personal information collected by AAPT will be solicited information, which will come into our possession as a result of our requesting information from you.

At times, AAPT may receive unsolicited personal information about you without having requested that information. Examples of unsolicited information may include additional or alternative contact details you happen to provide. If AAPT receives unsolicited personal information, we will, within a reasonable period after receipt of that information, determine whether were entitled to collect the information for the purposes set out under Use of your personal information below. If not, then will destroy or de-identify the unsolicited personal information

## What are the consequences of not providing Personal Information?

If you refuse to provide AAPT with the Personal Information we need to perform our services, we may not be able to provide you with telecommunications services or we may be restricted in the way those services can supplied.

## Collection Notices

Another purpose of this Privacy Policy is to give you notice of matters in accordance with Australian Privacy Principle 5. Where it is practicable to do so, AAPT will at the time, or a reasonable time after we collect your personal information, provide you with a collection notice setting out the following matters:

  * Why we collect your information
  * What happens if you don’t provide the information
  * Who we might we share your personal information with
  * Whether any of your information will be share with overseas organisations
  * How you can access your personal information or make a complaint

We refer you to our general Personal Information Collection Notice.

## Use of your personal information

AAPT respects your privacy. As a result, AAPT does not trade, rent-out or sell your personal information.

The primary purpose for which we use your personal information is to provide you with telecommunications services and related products and services.

In the course of providing a telecommunications service to you, we may also use your personal information for related purposes, which include the following:

  * processing your application, carrying out credit checking and scoring and ongoing credit management of your account;
  * provisioning or connecting your service;
  * network routing;
  * providing you with customer or helpdesk service;
  * credit checking;
  * billing you for that service and general account management;
  * investigating complaints or carrying out dispute resolution in relation to your service;
  * investigating and fixing faults in relation to your service;
  * performance monitoring of your services or testing or trialling activities;
  * following up any payments that you may owe us or processing refunds where required;
  * administering contractual agreements or arrangements necessary to provide services to you;
  * internal staff training
  * conducting market and product analysis and sending you product or services information.

## Direct marketing

We may also use your information to tell you about our other products and services or events and bundled offerings, provided by AAPT.

We may use your information to tell you about products and services or events and bundled offerings provided by AAPT in conjunction with either:

  * our related bodies corporate (including those outside Australia); or
  * our marketing partners with which we share our marketing and advertising activities; or
  * other businesses that produce or deliver products or services in conjunction with, or on behalf of, AAPT.

We will not provide your information to these entities for the purpose of them contacting you in respect of an event, product or service with which AAPT is not involved.

We may tell you about our products and services or events and bundled offerings via direct mail, electronic direct mail, unsolicited telemarketing calls or any other means of direct communication.

We may do this during the period you are a customer for AAPT and for a reasonable period after you leave us. 

You can always opt out of receiving direct marketing by emailing information@aapt.com.au and placing "OPT OUT" in the subject line and placing their contact information in the body of the email. We will process your request as soon as reasonably possible after receiving it and will not charge you for addressing your opt-out request.

## Contracting out services and disclosures

AAPT contracts out some services such as mailing, credit checking, provisioning, verification of sales and fault fixing to external providers. AAPT may disclose your personal information to these organisations but only so that they can perform services or supply goods in connection with the AAPT services.

AAPT may disclose your personal information to:

  * other telecommunications service and equipment providers,
  * AAPT's related bodies corporate,
  * resellers,
  * credit providers,
  * credit reporting agencies,
  * organisations to whom AAPT outsources services (such as mailhouses),
  * legal, financial and accounting advisers;
  * our marketing partners with which we share our marketing and advertising activities, and
  * other businesses that produce or deliver products or services in conjunction with, or on behalf of, AAPT.

At your request, AAPT may disclose your information to directory providers so that your information can appear in telephone directories.

Personal information shared with related bodies corporate may include your name, address and service history.

When we contract services or disclose your personal information, that personal information is either covered by contracts which protect your personal information or are subject to obligations which are substantially similar to the Australian Privacy Principles. AAPT may also disclose your personal information if required to by law. For example, we may disclose your personal information to government agencies for law enforcement purposes or to the operator of the Integrated Public Number Database.

## Your personal information in overseas locations

We operate both in Australia and overseas. Therefore we may need to share some of your personal information with organisations outside Australia.

AAPT may disclose some of your personal information that we hold to organisations located outside Australia in countries which do not have the same or substantially similar privacy laws, but only to the extent necessary to provide you with telecommunications services requested by you or to meet our business needs. We may also store your information in cloud or other types of networked or electronic storage. Where required, we will take reasonable steps to ensure that these overseas organisations do not breach the Australian Privacy Principles.

We have listed below the known countries in which the overseas organisations with which we share your personal information are located.

  * Canada
  * Europe
  * Japan
  * Malaysia
  * New Zealand
  * Singapore
  * The Philippines
  * United Kingdom
  * United States

It is not always practicable to know in which country your information may be held, for example, when your personal information is stored in cloud.  In these types of circumstances, disclosures may occur in countries other than those listed above.

Overseas organisations will be subject to their own laws and may be required to disclose information that we share with them. In those instances, we will not be responsible for that disclosure.

## How you can access your personal information

Generally, you have the right to see or obtain a copy of personal information about you that we may hold.

To request access to your personal information, please contact our Call Centre on (02) 9009 9009.

As long as we can verify your identity, the person you speak to may be able to provide you with the information you require over the telephone. If you wish to have a copy of any information, we will ask that you put your request in writing and either post or fax that request to us. Again, this is to ensure that we can verify your identity.

In some cases, we may need time to consider and respond to your request for access. If we need time to consider your request, we will acknowledge your request within 14 days and respond within a maximum of 30 days.

If for any reason we refuse to give you access to your information we will let you know why, in writing.

The circumstances in which we may refuse to give you access to personal information we hold about you include where giving you access:

  * would have an unreasonable impact on other people's privacy;
  * would prejudice any negotiations we are having with you;
  * would prejudice an investigation of unlawful activity;
  * would prejudice activities carried out by, or for, a law enforcement body.

If you believe that we hold personal information about you that you consider to be inaccurate, incomplete or out of date you should tell us by calling (02) 9009 9009. In most cases, we will amend any inaccurate, incomplete or out of date information. In some cases it is necessary for us to keep a record of what we know or understand to be correct at a particular time. However, in those circumstances, if you request, we will take reasonable steps to associate with the relevant record of your personal information a statement to the effect that you claim the information is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date. We would ask that you discuss your request with us by calling (02) 9009 9009.

## You may remain anonymous

When dealing with us, you have the option of not identifying yourselves or using a pseudonym.

You do not have this option where:

  * we are required or authorised by law, or a court or tribunal order to deal with individuals who have identified themselves;  or
  * it is impracticable to deal with you without verifying your identity.

## Security of your personal information

AAPT is committed to protecting your privacy and recognises its obligations to take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information from misuse and loss and from unauthorised access, modifications or disclosure both under the Privacy Act 1988 and the Telecommunications Act 1997.

## Security of your information while online

Our web server is capable of up to 128bit SSL encryption. Note however, that our web server can only chose the highest common level with your browser. If you use older browsers, you may find that it only supports 40bit or 56bit encryption.

## Cookies

Cookies are small text files that our web server may ask your web browser to store on your machine.

The cookie cannot tell who you are, or determine your personal details, and is not used to actually track your access, apart from making sure you are the same person over a given "session" online. Although you could turn off cookies and not normally have any problems accessing many parts of our sites, there are other parts of our web server that rely on cookies. For instance we may use a cookie to store information temporarily between various pages in a lengthy multi-part order form, or to store screen preferences.

We do not make use of 3rd party cookies on our website.

## Security of stored information

We take physical and electronic measures to secure your information. We store your personal information in password-protected servers that are in a restricted and monitored area. Access to this information is limited.

You also have a role in security of your personal information in some cases. For example, if you have been given access to our "Your Account", where you may pay your bill, look up call information and so on, it is your responsibility to protect your own personal access password.

## Other websites

Some of our websites contain links to other, external websites. The AAPT group of companies are not responsible for content or privacy policies websites that we do not want to operate.

## Website access logs

All accesses to pages on our websites are "logged". The sort of information contained in these logs cannot easily identify you personally, but instead contains such things as a list of the pages accessed, and the sort of browser used.

The information is used to check for attempts at "hacking", or other fraudulent activity, to indicate missing pages or other web server problems. It is periodically summarised to provide general statistics such as the number of people viewing particular parts of the site.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

From time to time, it may be necessary for us to review our Privacy Policy. We reserve the right to amend our Privacy Policy at any time and to notify you by posting an updated version on the AAPT website aapt.com.au.

## Privacy Complaints

You can raise any privacy related concern or complaint about breaches of your Privacy in writing or by phone to:

Privacy Officer  
AAPT Limited  
GPO Box 7041  
Sydney NSW 2001  
Telephone: (02) 9009 9009

## Organisational Details

Company name: AAPT Limited  
Contact Name: Rubina Lionatos  
Email address: aaptprivacy@aapt.com.au  
Actual address: 680 George Street, Sydney NSW 2000  
Postal Address: GPO Box 7041, Sydney NSW 2001  
Telephone: (02) 9009 9009
